人类的心脏是个巨大的肌肉,每分钟收缩挤压60次以上
The human heart is a giant muscle,squeezing and contracting over 60 times each min...
这里的血液是深紫色的
At this point,your blood is a deep purple.
因为氧气刚刚被释放到身体各个部位
Because it's just finished dropping off oxygen for all the parts of your body.
跟我来
Come on,follow me.
过来
Come on.
Ian.
Ian
我有个问题, 我还想去厕所
I have a question,and I need to go to the bathroom.
你想先做哪样?
Which would you like to do first?
问题
The question.
好的
Okay.
厕所在哪?
Where's the bathroom?
谁知道厕所在哪?
Who knows where the bathroom is?
我知道
I do.
你陪ian去厕所
Go with ian to the bathroom.
我不用上厕所
I don't have to go.
我们不是在学校, 不能单独行动
We're not at school.Nobody goes anywhere by themselves.
为什么?
Why?
为防止走失
In case you get lost.
或者有人绑架我们
Or in case somebody kidnaps us.
如果有人绑架ian, 顺便就把我绑了,我想和大家在一起
If somebody kidnaps ian,they'll kidnap me too.I want to stay with the class.
Michael, 陪ian去...
Michael,go with ian--
你怎么了?
Do you need help?
去帮我找个大人
I need you to find a grown-up.
小孩要出来了?
Is the baby coming?
谁陪我一起去?
Who should I take with me?
你没问题的, 到前台,或者找警卫来
You're fine.Go to the front desk,or--or find a security guard.
我要尿尿
I really have to pee.
上帝
God.
是小孩要出来吗? 我不知道怎么办
Is--is the baby coming?I don't know how to do this.
你没事吧, ian?
Are you okay,ian?
我没事
Yeah,sure.
我不这么觉得, 你在流血
I don't think you are.You're bleeding.
来人!
Help!
20块
20.
跟
Call.
什么你都敢跟
You'll call anything.
我的筹码多过你
My stack is bigger than your stack.
跟不跟吧?
You in or out?
按照相对体积来说,大猩猩的睾丸小于人类
You know that relative to their size,gorillas have smaller testicles than humans.
你也许可以大过猩猩,但大不过我
well,then you'd probably have an edge over a gorilla.But not over me.
灵长类的相对睾丸大小,与其对雌性的忠诚是负相关的
The reason is,primate teste size inversely corresponds to the fidelity of our females.
不要老拿我老婆的事呕我好不好?
Do you think there might be a better time to annoy me about myife?
- 我说的是扑克,- 没错
- I'm talking about poker.,- Right.
女人是魔鬼, 你赶走女人是明智的,跟, 扣牌还是加注, 不要废话
Women are evil.You're right to drive them away.Call,fold,or raise.Story time can wait.
我们比黑猩猩稍小一些,所以我们更忠诚
We're smaller and better than chimps,
比大猩猩更大更花心
bigger and worse than gorillas.
我们的理性,把忠诚和信任置于最高境界
For all our rationality,supposed trust and fealty to a higher power,
创造出规则和法律
our ability to create a system of rules and laws,
但是原始冲动大于所有的规则
our baser drives are more powerful than any of that.
我们想控制情感, 但做不到
We want to control our emotions,but we can'T.
如果我们快活, 那就没什么
If we're happy,things don't annoy us.
但另一方面, 如果我们拿到一手烂牌
If,on the other hand,we're sitting on crappy hole cards,
一点小事能让我们大为烦恼
little tiny things annoy us a whole lot more.
加注
I raise.
每次我加注都要跟我讲个烦人的故事?
So are you going to tell me an annoying story every time I raise?
那就太过分了
God,that would be annoying.
我跟
I call.
Cuddy医生? 有位病人在急诊室,Ian alston, 6岁
Dr. Cuddy?Got one of your patients in the E.R.Ian alston.Six years old.
噢, 我认识他, 什么问题?,我全押
oh,I know him.What's the problem?I'm all in.
泻血
Bloody diarrhea,
血行动力稳定, 不过肢体协调有问题
hemodynamically stable,but he's been developing some coordination problems.
好像是肠胃炎和脱水
It sounds like gastroenteritis and dehydration.
先给他输液,我返班的时候处理
Order fluids,and I'll take it on my service.
就看你了, House
Bet's to you,house.
做过头部扫描了?
They scan his head?
- 没有, 为什么要扫...,- 别玩花样, 跟不跟?
No,why would they scan--don't play games.You gonna call?
心率怎么样?
How's the heart rate?
稳定
Stable.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
House? 是肠胃炎,我不会走开的
House?It's gastroenteritis.I'm not going anywhere.
先输液, 让人告诉alan和sarah,我这边一完事就上去
Put the order in,and have someone tell alan and sarah that I'll be up when I'm done.
你跟不跟?
You in or out?
不跟
I'm out.
完美的唬牌
stone cold bluff.
你要多注意你的牌
You might want to spend a little more time paying attention to your cards,
而不是盯着我的胸部
and a little less time staring at my breasts.
它们也不成对
They don't match,either.
我出去喘喘气
I'm going to take some air.
眼睛看我的手指
Follow my finger with your eyes.
Cuddy医生什么时候会到?
How much longer will dr. Cuddy be?
从她在聚会上喝的mojitos酒的数量看
Well,given the number of mojitos she's knocking back at the party,
她还要3小时才能回复清醒
I'd say it's gonna be at least three hours before she's even conscious.
你也去了那个聚会?
weren't you at the same party?
我不喝酒
I don't drink.
伸手抓我的拐杖
I want you to reach out and grab my cane.
什么问题?
What's wrong?
你儿子的大脑失去对肌肉的控制了
Your son's brain is losing control of his muscles.
Cuddy医生说是腹泻造成的脱水
Dr. Cuddy's message said it was just dehydration from the diarrhea.
她错了
She's wrong.
他会好的吧?
Is he going to be all right?
不知道
I don't know.
你在那笼子里待过?
So were you in one of those cages?
没
No.
没没没,  笼子是给游客的
No,no,no.Those are for tourists.
你和一条大白鲨在水里
You were in the water with a great white.
当然, 这有什么,注意观察就好了
Sure.It's no big deal.You just have to keep an eye on them.
如果它们太靠近,打它的鼻子
If they get too close,punch 'em in the nose.
打跑了就没事
Send them on their way.
你信了
I had you going.
坏小子
You are mean.
你的肛裂怎么样了?
Hey,how's that anal fissure?
治好了? 还是仍在漏水?
Did it heal yet,or is it still draining?
不好意思,我以为你不会回来了
Oh,I'm sorry.I didn't realize you came back for seconds.
我以为楼梯间的那个女孩,够你今晚享受了
I figured that after that girl in the stairwell,you'd be done for the night.
他开玩笑
He's joking.
没有喉结, 手也小,这次应该是货真价实的了
No adam's apple,small hands.It's no surprises this time.
迟点见
I'll,see you later.
有个病例
Got a case.
你可以直接说, 不用给我捣乱
Well,you could've just said that.You didn't have to screw with me.
如果我不捣乱,你整晚都会惦记着上床
but if I didn't screw with you,you'd spend the whole night thinking you might get laid.
那样的你是无用的,还不如掐断你的希望
Which means you'd be useless.Better to extinguish all hope.
马上找foreman和cameron,到楼上找我
Get foreman and cameron and meet me upstairs,stat.
什么事这么急?
What's so urgent?
两个病例, 相同症状
Two cases,same symptoms.
6岁和70岁有什么相同点?
What do 6-year-olds and 70-year-olds have in common?
免疫系统都很差,可能是李氏杆菌病
Their immune systems don't work as well.Could be listeria.
已经查过了
Already checked for that.
白血病在两者都高发
Leukemia has a higher prevalence in both the young and old.
哮喘也是
So does asthma.
不不不
no,no,no.
都能得糖尿病
they can both get diabetes.
不
No.
将死之人和新生之人有很多共同点
The nearly dead and the newly bred have more in common
不同于青壮年
with each other than with people in the middle.
诡异
It's weird.
仿佛生命的循环
Some kind of circle of life thing.
这个小孩没有肾衰竭
This kid doesn't have kidney failure.
会有的
He will.
根据病历, 孩子只是吃坏了,老妇人也是--
Based on this file,the kid just ate some bad food.Was the old man--
这两人相距很远, 不论时间或空间
they were nowhere near each other in any of the four dimensions.
这个病例是12年前的
This case is 12 years old.
而这个是Cuddy的病人
And this case is cuddy'S.
她转交给我
She assigned it to me.
她同意你的判断?,认为这不是肠胃炎?
She agrees with you that this is something more than gastroenteritis?
她要不同意我就不会转给我, 对吗?
She wouldn't have assigned it to me if she didn't, would she?
我们在说什么?
What were we talking about?
两个病人, 各有两个症状相似
Two patients with two symptoms in common.
且有5个症状不相似
And five symptoms not in common.
你们还穿开裆裤的时候
While you were all wearing your "frankie says relax" t-shirts,
我在治疗这位73岁老妇,她经历了如下症状--
I was treating a 73-year-old woman who went through this progression of symptoms.
最后的一项...
The last of which was...
死亡
"Death"
不知道你们在医学院学过没有,这项是不可治疗的
in case any of you missed that class in med school,that one's untreatable.
小孩有了前两项
Kid's got the first two.
Esther在1小时20分钟后,发展到第三项
Took esther an hour and 20 minutes to go from two to three.
一天之内将抵达终点
And less than a day to make it all the way to the rear exit.
只是因为这孩子腹泻有血?
This is all because a child has some blood in his diarrhea.
他肚子疼
He's got a tummy ache.
如果有丝毫理由支持坏的一面,cuddy必会全力以赴
If there was any reason to think ithonything worse,cuddy would be all over it.
那好, 做个结肠镜
Great.Do a colonoscopy.
对一个很可能只是吃坏了的6岁小孩?
On a six-year-old kid who probably has nothing worse than some food poisoning?
如果发现紫色丘疹,给我切一片下来
If you happen to find any purple papules,do me a favor and grab a slice.
我要检查Erdheim-chester病
I want to check for erdheim chester.
迄今为止只有200例的疾病?
a disease that there have been what,maybe 200 reported cases of?Ever?
如果Esther家人允许我验尸
If esther's family had let me do an autopsy,
那就是第201例
there'd be 201.
发现什么?
see anything?
没有, 没指望能发现什么
no,and I don't expect to.
House通常不接病例
House usually avoids cases.
如果他从cuddy处偷病例,一定有原因
If he's actually stealing a case from cuddy,there's got to be a reason.
我不是第一次见这个病历
It's not the first time i've seen this file.
cameron来这里之前一个月
About a month before cameron was hired,
几个卡车司机也有相同的症状
some trucker came in here with these symptoms.
House认为他死定了
House decided he was dying.
两天之内做了脊椎穿, 抽骨髓,三次结肠镜
Two days and a spinal tap,bone marrow extraction,and three colonoscopies later,
最后诊断为吃了变质起司三明治,开了些止疼药打发回家了
we sent the guy home with a bunch of painkillers and a diagnosis of a bad cheese sandwich.
有个以前在这里上班的人说
One of the guys who worked here before me
house至少有三次试图拯救esther
said house tried to cure esther at least three other times.
你知道有的人能从面包上看出圣母像?
You know how people see the virgin mary in danishes and stuff?
12年前死去的病人, House不知道原因
Someone died 12 years ago,and house doesn't know why.
这个病例一直萦绕在House的眼前,剥落的油漆里, 云彩里, 这个小孩身上
House sees that case now in paint peeling,in clouds,and now in this poor kid.
Erdheim-chester病是,抗感染细胞的异常生长
Erdheim chester is an abnormal growth of some of the cells that fight infection.
是癌症么? 他现在看起来还好啊
Is that cancer?'Cause he seems okay now.
另外那个医生吓死我们了
Yeah,the other doctor kind of scared us about that.
没什么可怕的,只是做个测试, 估计结果是阴性
He shouldn't have.We're just testing.It'll probably be negative.
不明白, 你们不觉得他有那个病,但还是--
I don't understand.You don't think that's what it is,but you want to--
还是要做这些测试?
you want to do this thing to him anyway?
- 我们需要确定,- 没别的办法了吗?
--We need to be sure. --Isn't there any other way?
很快就好的
It shouldn't take long.
那些突起看着很像紫色丘疹
Those ridges look a lot like purple papules.
这不是紫色的, 是红色,很可能只是血疱
They're not purple,they're red.They're probably just blood blisters.
把活检针给我
Give me the biopsy needle.
这要花多长时间?
How long is this going to take?
算了, chase, "打跑鲨鱼"的故事虽然精彩,但她不会等你的
Forget it,chase.Your punching-out-the-shark story's good,but she's not waiting for you.
所以?
So?
我们不能确认出血的原因
We couldn't confirm the source of the bleeding.
但我们检出一些血疱
But we did biopsy some--blood blisters.
你是说丘疹
You mean papules.
快点cameron, 谁是对的?
Come on,cameron.Who's right?
Chase对了, 不是Erdheim-chester病
Chase is.Negative for erdheim chester.
我看看
Let me see.
- 如果不是Erdheim-chester病,- 就是我们之前说的
If it's not erdheim chester-- it's exactly what we said before.
普通的病毒性肠胃炎,我们可以回那个派对吗?
Garden variety viral gastroenteritis.Can we go back to the party?
做一次肾脏活检
Do a kidney biopsy.
Esther的肾脏停止-
Esther's shut down in exactly--
这孩子不是Esther
this kid is not esther.
你搞砸了, 她死了, 我很遗憾,不表示这孩子也要死
You screwed up,she died.I'm sorry.But that does not mean this kid is dying as well.
哇, 没泡到妞就这么怒,来吧
Jeez.You get testy when you don't get any fuzz.Come on.
测试结果怎样?
What did the test say?
结肠镜正常
colonoscopy was clean.
活检排除了Erdheim-chester病
And the biopsy was negative for erdheim chester.
这么说Ian会好的,只是病毒感染
so ian's going to be all right.It was just some sort of virus.
这怎么了?
What's that?
尿
Urine.
是褐色的
But it's brown.
Ian的肾脏失去功能了
Ian's kidneys are shutting down.
还说不是同个病?
Still think it's not the same case?
什么病导致泻血, 共济失调和肾衰竭?
so,what can cause bloody diarrhea,ataxia,and kidney failure?
做活组织检查
I'll go do a biopsy.
不必了
forget it.That battle's over.
不断上升的肌酐等于是说,"和你的肾拜拜吧"
His rising creatinine is his kidneys' way of saying,"go on without me."
其它症状怎么解释?
What explains everything?
O-157大肠杆菌可以导致泻血,并导致溶血性尿毒症
E. Coli ho:157 causes bloody diarrhea and leads to hemolytic uremic syndrome.
细菌释放的毒素导致肾功能失常
Toxins from the bacteria cause his kidneys to shut down.
可以先给他做血透析
We should start him on plasmaphoresis.
清晰准确, 值得表扬
Clear,concise,and completely plausible.
上次我就是这么做的, 无效,还有别的吗?
And exactly what I did last time.Didn't work.What else?
肺出血肾炎综合症
Good pasture's syndrome.
血液中的抗体导致肾功能失常并出血
Circulating antibodies cause kidney failure and bleeding.
但不会造成紫色丘疹
But not the purple papules.
考虑到esther接着出现脑症状,重金属中毒也有可能
if you throw in esther's next symptom--brain--makes me think heavy metal toxicity.
那他的血容应该很低, 他是44,Esther也未低于 -42
--His hematocrit would have to be low.It's at 44,and esther's never dropped below. --42.
你把病历都背下来了?
You have the file memorized?
这是我的幸运数字
It's my lucky number.
淋巴瘤?
What about lymphoma?
导致肾衰竭, 肠胃出血, 并能破坏大脑基底
Causes kidney failure,gi bleed,and can infiltrate the base of the brain.
Esther做过这些检查?
You check esther for that?
她没表现出这些症状...
She never showed any signs of...
如果他的淋巴瘤发展到这个地步,从血液和大脑能得到判断
if he has lymphoma this far advanced,we should be able to see it in his blood and brain.
Chase, 做血涂片和免疫化学反应,Foreman, 安排核磁共振
Chase,run a blood smear and immunochemistries.Foreman,get an mri.
我去呼Cuddy
I'll page cuddy.
不要去
No,you won'T.
她认为孩子是肚子疼
She thinks the kid has a stomach ache.
她会上来做以下两件事之一
She'll come right up here and do one of two things.
她同意我的看法, 我用不着她,她不同意我的看法, 我不想见她
If she agrees with me,I don't need her.If she disagrees,I don't want her.
容不得别人和你意见不同?
Can't handle people disagreeing with you?
她也许有不同的观点
She might have a different take on this.
下属可以和我意见相左, 这很健康
Subordinates can disagree with me all they want.It's healthy.
能停我职的人, 就不能这样...
People who can shut me down,on the other hand...
不用管cuddy, 我会让wilson把她拖住
forget cuddy.I'll have wilson keep her busy.
回答要简短并且不着边际,cuddy还在玩牌么?
Keep your answers short and discreet.Is cuddy still playing?
小妞...还在皮卡迪利广场
The chicken...is still in piccadilly square.
太好了, 她不会料到我们要攻打诺曼底
Brilliant.She'll never suspect that normandy is our target.
是House吗?
Is that house?
告诉他最低下注已经升到20/40,他快没钱了
Tell him that the blinds just went to 20/40,and he's running out of chips.
她玩的怎么样?
how's she doing?
出什么情况了?
Well,what's going on?
你走的时候, 很明显-
The way you took off,something's obviously--
聊天很愉快, 但我们还有场牌要打,她玩的怎么样?
love to chat.But got a game to play.How's she doing?
病人还在维生器上, 我们要拔掉管子
The patient is on life support.We're about to pull the plug.
你是在说我?
Are you talking about me?
你拿的什么牌?
What have you got?
高剂量心脏药物
those sound like high-dose cardio meds.
两张红桃
Two hearts.
你有顺子?
You got the flush?
还在等化验结果
Still waiting on the final labs.
她在喝seltzer矿泉水?
She drinking her seltzer?
不, 水没有问题
No.Hydration is not a problem.
她在唬你, 逼她全下了
means she's bluffing.Push her all in.
跟, two pairs
Call.Two pair.
让我看看你的红心
Show me your hearts.
梅花7
Seven of clubs.
啊糟糕, 我搞错了
Oh,dear.Sounds like I messed up.
你得和她多纠缠一会儿了
You're gonna be stuck with her for a while.
再联系
Talk to you soon.
太好了
Yes.
为什么要拍头部的片子?
Why are you taking a picture of his head?
我们在查淋巴瘤, 但是--
We're looking for lymphoma,but--
不是那个Erdheim什么的病,也不是肾病, 但他的肾就是不行了
so it's not erdheim something.And it's not his kidneys.But his kidneys are failing.
什么...哪里能找到Cuddy医生?
What--where's dr. Cuddy?
House医生提到了另一个病例
Dr. House mentioned another case.
是不是曾经有个人,和ian的病一模一样?
Is there another patient with the same--same thing that ian has?
不尽相同
Not...exactly.
那是什么意思?
What does that mean?
House医生以前有个病人,表现出的症状和你儿子一样
Dr. House had a patient a while back who exhibited the same symptoms as your son.
你知道是什么病?
Then you know what's wrong?
不
No.
那是什么意思?
So what do you know?
我们知道这个病大致的发展方向
We know the likely course the disease will take.
是什么?
which is?
- 她的多个器官衰竭,- 她最后怎么了?
She had multiple system failures-- --what happened to her?
入院24小时后死去
She died 24 hours after her admission.
Alston先生或者太太,能不能来帮个忙?
Mr. Or mrs. Alston,would you mind giving me a hand?
他总是乱动
he's having trouble sitting still.
这样不可能得到结果
It's impossible to get the detail we need.
我想你们的声音可以安慰他
So I figured he might feel more comfortable hearing your voices.
Ian, 亲爱的?
Ian,honey?
不要动
Just sit still.
很快就好了, 我们就在这里
You'll be done in a moment.We're here with you.
我怕
I'm scared.
没事的, 宝贝, 那只是...
It's okay,honey.It'S...
是一个大照相机,他们要给你的头拍照
it's only a big camera.It's going to take a picture of your head.
在家里, 你不是最喜欢我给你照相的吗?
You love it when I take your picture at home,don't you?
照那个相也要不动啊, 是不是?
And you have to hold still for that too,right?
这和那个不一样
But this isn't like that.
我知道听着吓人, Ian
I know it's scary,ian.
但你可以做到
But you can do it.
你已经是个小大人了
You're getting to be so grown up.
所以...只要坚持不动,一下子就好了
So just...hold perfectly still.Just for a little bit.
妈妈, 你哭了?
Mommy,are you crying?
不, 不是的宝贝,我只是累了
No.No,honey.I'm just tired.
好吧, 我尽量
Okay.I'll try.
- 他的大脑基底可见小块物质, 我们认为,- 垂体?
The base of his brain has been infiltrated by a small mass.We think--pituitary?
看起来像,这能解释低血压
Looks that way.Explains the low blood pressure.
基本符合淋巴瘤
Pretty much confirms the lymphoma.
如果我们以强的松治疗esther...
If we'd started esther on prednisone...
看见淋巴瘤了么?
did anyone see the lymphoma?
没有, 只看见一团,位置相当靠近--
no,we saw a mass. The location was consistent with--
血液里也没见到
didn't see any in the blood,either.
白细胞未见细长, 也没有异常核型
White blood cells show no spindling or abnormal nuclei.
免疫化学反应没发现什么, 不是淋巴瘤
Nothing on immunochemistries,either.It's not lymphoma.
那是一列火车
It's a train.
我们不知道是什么火车
We don't know what kind of train.
- 我渴了,- 这里关门了
- I'm thirsty,- It's closed.
没有
It's not now.
我们还有一优势
We got one advantage.
我们知道病情的走向
We know where the tracks are going.
知道终点是死亡...
The fact that the end of the line is death...
这是个优势?
is an advantage?
只要我们知道, 就是优势
The fact that we know is an advantage.
也许我们可以抢先一步
Means maybe we can get ahead of it.
下一站是肝脏,在此之前我们还有...90分钟
Next station is the liver.We've got...about 90 minutes before it gets there.
也许我们可以砍倒一棵树挡住路
Maybe we can cut down a tree across the line just outside of town.
我去做超声波
I'll do an ultrasound.
不, 治疗措施告诉我们的更多, 更快
No,treatment will tell us more,faster.
不知道治什么, 怎么出治疗措施?
How can we start treatment if we have no idea what we're treating for?
所有的都治
Treat him for everything.
乙酰半胱氨酸, 干扰素, 水飞蓟素
Give him acetylcysteine.And interferon.And silymarin.
以及任何能想到的保肝药
And whatever else you can think of to protect the liver.
发生什么事?
What's going on?
随便看点电视,你怎么样?
Oh,just catching up on some tv.How are you doing?
多谢你刚才的指点,病人的病情急剧好转
Well,thanks to your last consult,the patient has improved dramatically.
告诉house, 病人要杀医生了
Tell house the patient is about to kill the doctor.
- 他说病人,- 听见了, 你拿什么牌?
- She says the pa-,-I heard.What do you got?
cuddy刚刚加注了, 而且
Well,cuddy just raised,and,
你拿了对子?
you're paired.What?
对9?
Nines?
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
比这小的牌, 你不会这么兴奋
Anything lower,you wouldn't sound so excited.
如果比J大
Jacks or higher,
你的声音会变得好像,会计部的debbie坐在你腿上
your voice sounds like debbie from accounting is sitting in your lap.
问问cuddy她能不能大过一对3
Ask cuddy if she can beat a pair of threes.
你想干什么? 如果你想害我
Wait,what's--what's going on?If you're going to mess with me,
当面做不是更好玩?
wouldn't it be more fun to do it in person?
那倒是
Yes,it would.
你能大过对3么?
can you beat a pair of threes?
她怎么做?
what did she do?
我让病人用口服液
I left orders for po fluids,doctor.
不要用暗语了, 她知道是我
Enough with the codes.She obviously knows it's me.
她在喝seltzer
She's drinking her seltzer.
她停下了?
Did she stop?
是的
Yes.
全押
Go all in.
可是...
.but...
照做就是
just do it.
你对这次筹款也太热心了吧
You couldn't care less about this charity event.
你说了不想害我
You claim not to be messing with me.
-  显然, 你要么是想让我-,- 闭嘴
- Obviously,you're either trying to keep me-,- shut up.
上次, 我希望你继续玩下去,现在仍是
Look,last time,I wanted the game to go on.I still do.
也就是说, 这次必须让你赢
That means that this time,you get to win.
稍等
Hold on.
扣牌
I fold.
house, 你没事吧?
house,are you sure you're okay?
药物似乎有效, 肝脏还没有出问题
Meds seem to be working.Liver's holding its own.
很好
Good.
血小板在降低
But the platelets are dropping.
更好
Even better.
为什么? 这表示他的病加重了
Why?It means he's getting sicker.
这是新现象, 新的总是好的
It's new.New is good.
因为老现象必死无疑
Because old ended in death.
我喘不过气
I can't breathe.
怎么了?
What's happening?
我们得给他上呼吸机了
we had to put him on a ventilator.
他又回到esther的轨道了
He's back on esther's path.
我们让火车少停了几站
And we managed to make the train skip a few stations.
说明没有12小时了,他可能只有不到2小时
Which means that instead of 12 hours,he's probably got less than two.
引出了下面的问题,为什么? 我们做了什么?
Which begs the question,why?What did we do?
乙酰半胱氨酸会破坏肺功能
Acetylcysteine could mess with the lungs.
破坏, 不是在20分钟内彻底关闭
Mess with them.Not shut them down in 20 minutes.
干扰素调节免疫系统
Interferon modulates the immune system.
它可以影响血液癌细胞,就像白血病一样
It could affect a cancer of the blood,like one of the leukemias.
它不是加速, 而是减速
It doesn't speed them up,it slows them down.
所有的都减速?
It slows down all 500 of them?
谁知道这时候到哪里去找肿瘤科医生?
Anybody know where we can find an oncologist at this hour?
干扰素对白血病有哪些效果?
What effects would interferon have on leukemia?
取决于什么类型的,可有好效果, 也可能是坏效果
Depends on what type.Could make it better,could make it worse.
4年肿瘤科就学了这个
Four-year fellowship to learn that.
告诉house, 如果他想玩牌就下来
tell house if he wants to play cards,he should get his ass back down here and play.
听见了?
You hear that?
她想让我挂掉, 说明她心虚,全押上
She wants me off the phone.Means she's vulnerable.Go all in.
可是这个聚会还有不到3小时结束
But,um,the party's over in less than three hours.
不到2小时就结束
it's over in less than two hours.
说明你要么是有3张同花,或者有对3
Which means you either have three of a kind,or just 3s.
我猜是有对3, 我加500
I'm guessing 3s.I bet 500.
全押上
Go all in.
你这明显是害我,你还不如--
You obviously want to bust me.Why would you--
你要不押上, 我会告诉这栋楼里的人,你涂脚趾甲油
either you go all in,or I tell everybody in the building that you wear toenail polish.
我全押上
I'm all in.
我跟
I'll call.
我认准了你有对3, 不过,即使你有3个3...
I'm betting you have a pair of threes,but even if you have three...
也大不过3条9
it's not going to beat trip nines.
哦不, 哦不 不不,这下可要肉痛了
Oh,oh no.Oh,no.That's gotta hurt.
什么情况?
What happened?
我的同花顺大过1对9
I just killed two birds with one straight.Good-bye.
行, 继续玩
Fine.Keep playing.
但你要为我推荐一个肿瘤科医生
But I need you to recommend a good oncologist.
如果几分钟内还没人,这个6岁病人会死
Because if I don't get one up here in the next few minutes,I got a dead six-year-old.
如果你需要帮助 , 开口即可,用不着玩这些
if you need help,ask.These games are insane.
游戏的成功率高些
Games have a higher success rate.
看不出来哪里像白血病,做过骨髓抽检么?
well,I don't see anything that looks like leukemia.You do a bone marrow biopsy?
没时间
No time.
如果是白血病
even if there is an occult blood cancer,
干扰素不会导致恶化
you wouldn't expect interferon to make it worse.
绝对没这么快
Certainly not this fast.
什么这么快?
What would move this fast?
自体免疫病,被自身的防御系统攻击
autoimmune diseases.If his body's own defenses are attacking him,
激活免疫系统就等于火上浇油
then beefing them up is just going to put fuel on the fire.
大脑和肺可能有结节病
Sarcoidosis could be in his brain and lungs.
胸透没发现肺门淋巴结增大
No,no enlarged hilar lymph nodes on his chest x-ray.
全身性症状表明可能是,少儿类风湿性关节炎
The systemic nature suggests juvenile rheumatoid arthritis.
或者"川崎病"
Or kawasaki's disease.
不是川崎病, 它不出现在老人身上
Can't be kawasaki'S.Doesn't affect the elderly.
这个...是小孩的X光
these...this is a kid's x-ray.
House以前的一个病人...
House had another patient...
她有没有川崎病难说,而这个孩子...
who may or may not have had kawasaki'S.This kid,on the other hand...
他制造出抗体, 侵蚀动脉壁
he makes antibodies that are eating the inside of his arteries.
逐一破坏重要器官的血液供应
Choking off blood to his major organs one by one.
首先是消化道, 然后肾脏,大脑, 现在是肺
First the gi tract,then the kidneys,then the brain,now the lungs.
谁能想出来, 为什么老人不得川崎病?
Can anyone think of a reason why kawasaki's can't affect the elderly?
而不是这件事实?
Other than that it doesn't?
好
Nice.
可以用血检确定, 自身抗体检测,沉降率--
we can confirm with blood work.We need an ana,sed rate--
化验至少要两小时
labs will take two hours.
老妇人的沉降率多少?
What was the old lady's sed rate?
高达98
elevated. 98.
不能用另一个病人的化验结果诊断这个
You can't use another patient's labs to diagnose kawasaki's disease.
这是什么禁忌么?
Is that like a dare or something?
没时间纠错
You don't have time to be wrong.
那好, 我们到川崎病居住的地方找
Fine.We'll look for kawasaki where he lives.
Ian的冠状动脉
Ian's coronary arteries.
这个病人
This other patient.
老妇人, 叫Esther?
The old lady.Esther?
你有没有听说过白鲸记?
Have you read moby dick?
是一本书?
It was a book?
- 那是10年前,- 12年
- It was ten years ago.,- 12.
偏执是危险的
Obsession is dangerous.
只有当你坐着一条木船,而你偏执的对象是条鲸鱼
Only if you're on a wooden ship and your obsession is a whale.
我觉得我很安全
I think I'm in the clear.
你知道这是个比喻吧?
You do realize it's a metaphor?
你知道比喻的作用,就是吓唬人们不做某事
You do realize that the point of metaphors is to scare people from doing things
通过告诉他们, 如果你做了
by telling them that something much scarier
将会有件更恐怖的事情发生
is going to happen than what will really happen.
我真希望能用个比喻更好地表达
God,I wish I had a metaphor to explain that better.
回去玩牌吧, 别担心,我不会被女巫吃了的
Go back to the game.Don't worry.I'm not going to get eaten by witches.
冠状动脉没事, 没有动脉瘤
coronary arteries clear.No aneurysms.
改变模式, 看看血流
Flip the mode.Let's see the flow.
那个女人怎么死的?
how did that other woman die?
她呼吸衰竭
She went into respiratory distress.
心脏和肝脏已经-
Her heart and liver were already com--
不, 她疼吗?
no.Did she suffer?
痛苦吗?
Was she in pain?
我不知道
I don't know.
血流稳定, 没有血块, 没有扰动
Laminar flow.No blood clots,no ragged edges.
该死, 关掉吧,我们在浪费时间
damn.Shut it down.We're just wasting time.
看右心室
Look at the right atrium.
不是川崎病
That's not kawasaki'S.
不
No.
很小,  但确实有
it's small. But it's there.
Esther的心脏里没有肿块
Esther didn't have a mass in her heart.
Ian还年轻
Ian's younger.
他不容易被打倒
He can take more of a pounding.
Esther在疾病到达心脏之前就死了,这病造成肿块并加速死亡
Esther died before the disease reached her heart.The disease made a mass and made it fast.
- 可能是细菌感染,- 肌肉 - 结缔组织
Could be bacteria.Muscle.connective tissue.
这孩子不能再接受猜测
the kid can't take any more theories.
我们只知道, 不论这肿块是什么,肯定和这病有关
Only thing we know is that whatever that mass is,that's what he's got.
需要切一片下来,做活组织检查
We need a piece of it.I'm doing a biopsy.
我关上百叶窗
I'll shut the blinds.
不, 让他们看
No,let them watch.
有观众我的表现才好
I do my best work on the big stage.
穿过上腔静脉
Passing through the superior vena cava.
进入心室
You're in the atrium.Pull back.
接触到心壁
Hit the wall of the heart.
在健康人身上做这个很简单
These procedures would be so much simpler if we could do them on healthy people.
又退出
And out again.
- 心室颤动,- 心脏停跳, 我叫人急救
- V. Fib,- Cardiac arrest.Call it.
快点, 电板, 快点
Come on. Paddles.Come on.
好了
Clear.
再来
And again.
- 没反应,- 再来
- Nothing,- Again.
你有表么?
have you got a clock on this?
你这样还要多久?
How much longer you going to ep doing this?
好了
Clear.
等下, 有反应了
Wait.Got something.
缓过来了
He's back.
你要干什么?
what are you doing?
继续刚才没做完的
I'm doing what we came here to do.
那差点要了他的命
It almost killed him.
我知道, 我就在这里,把真空管给我
I know.I was right here.Give me a vacutainer.
他的大脑缺氧超过8分钟
His brain's been oxygen-deprived for over eight minutes.
可能剩不下什么了, 你已经--
There might be nothing left.You might be--
通知他的父母,真空管在哪里?
you should tell the parents.Where the hell is that vacutainer?
他会怎么样?
so.What's he got?
大脑损伤
Brain damage.
极有可能, 我是问在这之前
Good chance.I was talking about before that.
你难道不担心-
You're not worried about--
无可挽回的事, 我尽量不去担心
things I can't do anything about?I try not to.
说的好像你可以轻松忘记
Things just roll off you like water off a duck.
组织细胞增生
Histiocytosis.
不太可能在73岁病人身上
Very unlikely in a 73-year-old.
不管是什么, 都很蹊跷
Whatever this is,is very unlikely.
快点, 再来点主意, 加油伙计们
Come on,more ideas.Let's go,people.
遗传病可以形成肿块,结节性硬化症
Genetic disorders could cause masses everywhere.Tuberous sclerosis.
如果是遗传性的, 他一出生便有,为何现在发生?
If it's genetic,he's had it all his life.Why now?
不知道, 不过有可能
I don't know.It sure fits nice enough.
我们并未排除白血病
We haven't ruled out leukemia yet.
或者肉瘤, 可能是多发软组织肿瘤
Or sarcoma.He could have multiple soft tissue tumors.
或者结节病, 多发神经纤维瘤
or sarcoidosis.Multiple neurofibromatosis.
成软骨细胞瘤
chondrocytomas.
玩的怎么样? 赢了?
How's it going?Win?
我被愤怒的家长叫来了
I got called away by the angry parents of a patient.
你们3个人在,没一个人想到要阻止他
There are three of you here.None of you had the sense to stop him.
没想到拿起电话找我
To pick up a phone and call me.
我告诉他们你会把病例转给我
I told them you'd signed off.
家长愤怒, 因为孩子要死了,这可以理解
The parents are mad because their kid is dying.It's understandable.
如果他不死, 家长就不会生气了
But if he doesn't die,they won't be mad anymore.
大脑损坏了, 他们照样生气
If he's brain-damaged,they might still be a little ticked.
我要救他就必须那样做
I had to do it to save him.
你那样做是为了诊断esther
You had to do it to diagnose esther.
你不惜杀死一个6岁小孩
You may have killed a six-year-old
因为你对12年前死去的一个女人不能释怀
because you're obsessed with a woman who's been dead for 12 years.
有时候你会失手, house,你不是上帝
Sometimes you lose,house.You're not god.
他还没死
He's not dead yet.
不, 这里没你事了,这是我的病人, 回你的家
No,but you're done with him.It's my case now.Go home.
去飙车, 躲在小黑屋里郁郁寡欢,就是别靠近Ian了
Go ride your motorcycle.Go brood in a dark room.Just don't go near ian again.
还有别的吗? 还是只有这7项
So,anything else?Or is it just these seven?
放手吧, house 她是对的
Drop it,house.She's right.
不对, 你知道她不对
No,she's not.You know she's not.
我们应该叫她
We should have called her.
我很惊讶你没有
I'm surprised you didn'T.
无论如何你要放手了,我们不能再碰Ian
you're going to have to find a way to let this go--we can't go near ian.
我们不用碰他
We don't need to go near him.
我们拿到了他的肿瘤
We have his tumor.
Cuddy也许说对了,我们没有按照指南
Cuddy may be right that we screwed up the protocol.
对于我的偏执, 她也许说对了
She may be right about my screwed-up obsession.
在医学上我是正确的
But I am right about the medicine.
这点样本能做几个检测?
How many tests can we do with that?
我们治好这孩子, 就不存在任何问题,几项?
Look,we cure the kid,we solve everybody's problems.How many?
两项没问题
Maybe two good pieces.
最多能做几项?
How many okay pieces?
3项已经勉强
Three would be pushing it.
3项测试, 7个选择
Three tests,seven choices.
好, 先做哪项?
Okay,what's first?
结节病似乎最有可能
sarcoidosis seems most likely.
太有可能了, cuddy绝对会想起来
Yeah,so likely that cuddy's going to think of that all on her own.
整个人都在她手上,让她去做这个
She's got the kid's whole body to play with.Let her do that test.
下一个?
What's next?
这么快的速度不可能是扩散
It's moving too fast to be spreading.
病灶肯定早就在了-
It has to be growing from something that's already--
遗传病——结节性硬化症
genetic disorder--tuberous sclerosis.
或者是免疫系统, 组织细胞增生
Or it's his immune system.Histiocytosis.
组织细胞增生的报道多集中在老人身上-
There are more documented cases of Histiocytosis.
结节性硬化症则不然,从这个开始
amongst older people than tuberous sclerosis.Let's start with that.
要鸡翅还是鸡腿?
Wing or drumstick?
需要再多点
Gonna need a little more than that.
再多就超过三分之一了
A little more is more than a third.
不给我们切够就要重复试验...
If we have to repeat this test because you didn't cut us enough...
加入1微升免疫过氧化酶
I'm adding one microliter of the immunoperoxidase.
两微升, 我不想被House找麻烦
Make it two. I don't want house biting off our heads
只因为我们不能确定显红色
because we weren't sure if it turned red or not.
没有显红色
that's definitely not red.
可能还是的细胞异常增生,只不过在另一种组织
your problem could still be an abnormal cell growth,but a different cell line.
肉瘤? 肌细胞遍布全身,这可以解释发病部位
sarcoma?Muscle cells are throughout his body.Would explain the geography.
6岁小孩更有可能是遗传病,结节性硬化症
genetic disorder is far more likely in a six-year-old.Tuberous sclerosis.
这一般不造成消化道出血
Pretty unlikely to cause a gi bleed.
时间序列符合
The time course fits.
foreman, 你同意他们两个,你还真会玩
So,foreman,you agree with both of them.Thanks for playing.
如果剩下的组织还能做两项,为什么不都做?
If we have enough tissue for two tests,why not do both?
我们不必这么思考
Then we don't have to think as hard.
摆脱做选择的压力,可以让我们更好的思考
Taking the pressure off the choice makes us less likely to think critically.
肉瘤在6岁和70岁人身上都是多发的
Sarcoma is more likely to hit a 6- and a 70-year-old.
结节性硬化症
Tuberous sclerosis it is.
你认为肉瘤的几率小?
You think sarcoma is less likely?
几率大, 但是检测方法不甚可靠
It's more likely.The test for it,on the other hand,is less reliable.
nestin阴性
nestin's negative.
这好解释
Well,that's okay.
如果肿瘤细胞未成熟,KI-67蛋白不会消失
If the tumor cells haven't matured,the ki-67 protein wouldn't have turned off.
如果我们不能解决这个,会发生什么事?
What happens if we don't solve this?
小孩会死
The kid dies.
我指将来的12年
I mean for the next 12 years.
Ki-67蛋白阴性
Ki-67's negative.
PCH抗原阴性
And pch antigen is negative.
Mighty casey剩最后一期了
Mighty casey's down to his last strike.
Mighty casey早就停了
Mighty casey struck out.
多谢, 我本来计划这周末看的
Thanks a lot. I was going to read that this weekend.
成软骨细胞瘤,结缔组织在所有地方都有
chondrocytoma.Connective tissue has been in all the places we've been looking.
孩子病的太厉害了,最好还是检测肉瘤
The kid is too sick for that.We're better off testing for sarcoma.
测结节性硬化症时,就应该看到一些指征
we would have seen signs of that when we tested for tuberous sclerosis.
在显微镜下肿瘤细胞和肌细胞差不多
Tumor cells look like muscle under the microscope.
不是的, 看上去像脂肪
No,they didn'T.They looked like fat.
我赞成神经纤维瘤
I vote for neurofibromatosis.
为什么?
Why?
因为其它的选择更差
Because the other choices suck worse.
给我点时间
Give me a minute.
你要我出去?
You want me out of here?
你查出新的东西?
You come up with anything?
没有
No.
我们明天再说
We can talk about it tomorrow.
我...我赢了扑克比赛
I,um,I won the poker tournament.
我彻底打败了商务服务部的berman
I totally played this guy berman from business affairs.
我拿了好牌,  但我不声张,只跟不加
I got great cards.But I don't bet.Just call,no raises.
Berman牌面是一对K
Berman pairs his king on the flop.
我一直跟他, 然后看自己的底牌
I keep calling,the river turns,I check.
他受不了了, 全部押上,他确信能赢
He can't stand it.He goes all in.He's sure he's won.
我跟了, 亮牌
I call,I flip 'em.
一对A
Pocket aces.
我把他放倒了
I nailed his ass.
王牌总是隐藏着
The aces were hiding all along.
测erdheim-chester病
Test him for erdheim chester disease.
erdheim-chester病?,它甚至不在名单上
Erdheim chester?That's not even on the list.
因为我们已经做过,是阴性
Because we already did it.He tested negative.
esther也是
So did esther.
疾病会撒谎
The disease lied.
是啊, 肿瘤骗到你了,疾病不撒谎
yeah,the tumor's got it in for you.Diseases don't lie.
好吧, 疾病不撒谎,只是慢慢地玩弄我们
Fine,it didn't lie.It slow played us.
活检的是结肠,当时还没到达消化道
We biopsied the colon,but it hadn't reached the gi tract yet.
现在它到了, 还到了肝, 肺...
It's there now. It's in his liver,his lungs...
我们希望它在那里
you want it to be there.
这样你12年前就不算失手了
Because then you didn't screw up 12 years ago.
不能不能浪费样品,做一项已经排除的测试
We can't waste our one test on the one disease we know it's not.
动手吧
Run the test.
你确定?
You sure about this?
等等, 我再考虑下, 别催我,赶紧开始测试
Wait,let me think about that.Don't pressure me.Just run the damn test.
看上去像巨噬细胞
cells look like macrophages.
不错的开始
That's a good start.
慢慢来, 大声地报出来
Take your time and say it loud.
Cd 68阳性
Cd 68 positive.
开始治疗
Start the treatment.
esther现在可以安息了?
So esther can rest peaceful now?
你走运了
You got lucky.
跟不跟?
You gonna call?
我的策略...
What I do...
不光是根据牌面
is not just based on the flip of a card.
你猜的, 走运而已
You guessed.You got lucky.
猜中了
It fit.
有很大可能是肉瘤或结节性硬化症
It could just as easily have been sarcoma or tuberous sclerosis.
不, 没那么大可能
No,not just as easily.
也许吧
Maybe not.
但不是不可能
But it wasn't impossible.
你跟不跟?
Are you going to call?
知道吗, 根据身体的比例
You know,relative to its size,
所有动物中阴茎尺寸最大的是藤壶
the barnacle has the largest penis of any animal.